Guide to the Robert Davies Papers on Hanson Baldwin
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Davies papers on Hanson Baldwin
1936-2005
MS 1984
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.7
(15 boxes)
The Robert Davies papers on Hanson Baldwin contain correspondence, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files, interview transcripts and audiocassettes relating to Davies's book: Baldwin of the Times: Hanson W. Baldwin, a Military Journalist's Life, 1903-1991.
Davies, Robert B., 1933-
Scope and Contents
The Robert Davies papers on Hanson Baldwin contain correspondence, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files, interview transcripts and audiocassettes relating to Davies's book: Baldwin of the Times: Hanson W. Baldwin, a Military Journalist's Life, 1903-1991.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged by topic.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Custodial History
Gift of Robert Bruce Davies, 2012.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Bruce Davies taught at Minnesota State University Moorhead for thirty-two years, retiring in 1998. He is the author of Baldwin of the Times: Hanson W. Baldwin, a Military Journalist's Life, 1903-1991 and Peacefully Working to Conquer the World: Singer Sewing Machines in Foreign Markets, 1854-1920.
Biographers; Journalists -- United States -- Biography; War correspondents -- United States -- Biography; Baldwin, Hanson Weightman, 1903-1991; Davies, Robert B., 1933-; Baldwin, Hanson Weightman, 1903-1991
- Correspondence
  - Davies, Robert
    - Baldwin, Hanson, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Oakes, John B., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur O., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    - Talese, Gay, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin, Hanson W.
    - To grandchildren, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Worthington, Joe
      - 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1952-1980s (Box 1, Folder 6-13)
      - Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Worthingtons and others, 1976-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Worthington, Kathy, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) records on Hanson Baldwin
  - Subject files
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18-26)
  - Telephone transcripts, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Transcripts
  - Interviews with Hanson Baldwin by John T. Mason, Jr.
    - Interview #1 with Index to interviews 1-8, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Interview #2, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Interview #3, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Interview #4, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Interview #5 and appendix, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Interview #6, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Interview #7, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Interview #8, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Recollections recorded for grandchildren in 1983, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Baldwin-Davies interviews
    - 1985 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 1986 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Oakes, John B. interview, 1986 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Interview with Hanson Baldwin and his wife, Helen Bruce Baldwin on 5 August 1987, 2002 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Media influence, tapes I and II, 7 September 1987, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Baldwin tape of June 1989 in reply to Davies' 25 April letter, 2002 May 9-11 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Potter, Mrs. Barbara [Baldwin] interview, 2005 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Audiocassettes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  General
  The "Recollections" and "Media Influences" recordings are dubs of originals which were returned to Hanson Baldwin. There are multiple copies of some portions, which are arranged in various sequences.
  - Baldwin, Hanson
    - Recollections
      - Part I, 1985 (Box 2)
      - Part II, 1985 (Box 3)
      - Parts III and IV, 1985? (Box 4)
      - Part V, 1985? (Box 5)
      - 1987 September 7 (Box 8)
    - Interviews
      - 1985 June 22 (Box 6)
      - At Roxbury, 1986 July 10 (Box 7)
    - Media Influences
      - Part I, 1987 September 7
        - Copy 1 (Box 8)
        - Copy 2 (Box 2)
        - Copy 3 (Box 3)
      - Part II, 1987 September 7
        - Copy 1 (Box 9)
        - Copy 2 (Box 10)
    - Response to questions in Robert Davies' 25 April 1989 letter, 1989 June (Box 11)
  - Baldwin, Hanson and Helen Bruce, 1987 August 5 (Box 12)
  - Others
    - Oakes, John B., 1986 November 19 (Box 13)
    - Potter, Mrs. Barbara [Baldwin] -- at her home in Woodbury, Connecticut, 1987 August 5 (Box 14)
    - Crabtree, Elizabeth Baldwin -- at her home in Ridgewood, New Jersey, 1987 August 9 (Box 15)